Inventory of the William Russell Philp collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Item 42. Fragment of a report on German youth, undated (Box 4)
  Includes sections on: school youth, working youth and returned soldiers, and young women; education (schools and their difficulties, denazification, teachers today and tomorrow); factors affecting youth (the home, the church, political parties, youth organizations); the occupation ("Demokratie," the American soldier, press and radio); and an epilogue.
- Item 43a. "Von Versailles bis Moskau," Baron Kurt von Lersner, former president of the German peace delegation, undated (Box 4)
  Includes English translation ("From Versailles to Moscow").
- Item 43b. "Territorial questions," Baron Kurt von Lersner, 1947 (Box 4)
- Item 44a. "Mein politischer Werdegang" [Graf Lutz Schwerin von Krosigk], 1946 September 14 (Box 5)
  Includes English translation ("My Political Career").
- Item 44b. "Vereinigte Staaten von Mitteleuropa" [Graf Lutz Schwerin von Krosigk], [1947] (Box 5)
  Includes English translation ("The United States of Central Europe").
- Item 45a. "Internment Camps,", undated (Box 5)
- Item 45b. "The Munich Agreement,", undated (Box 5)
  See also: Item 46d.
- Item 45c. "The Tragedy of Democracy in Germany" [Graf Lutz Schwerin von Krosigk], circa 1947 (Box 5)
- Item 45d. "Expelled to Death: Poland and the Potsdam Agreement" [Graf Lutz Schwerin von Krosigk], [1947] (Box 5)
- Item 45e. "Einige Beobachtungen über gewisse Methoden in der Behandlung der Bevölkerung im russisch besetzten Gebiet,", undated (Box 5)
  Includes English translation ("Notes on Current Methods of Treatment of the Inhabitants of the Russian Zone of Occupation").
- Item 45f. English translation of a report by a German national on treatment by the CIC [American Counter Intelligence], undated (Box 5)
- Item 45g. "Nuernberg,", undated (Box 5)
  Account of treatment of witnesses and accused at Nuremberg.
- Item 45h. "The Sentence of Nuernberg,", undated (Box 5)
- Item 45j. Unsigned account by a prisoner of his interrogations at Nuermberg, undated (Box 5)
- Item 46a. "Contributions to an Economic Plan for Germany,", undated (Box 5)
- Item 46b. "Taxes and Monetary Reform,", undated (Box 5)
- Item 46c. "Why Does Democracy Make No Progress in Germany?,", undated (Box 5)
- Item 46d. "The Munich Agreement" [Graf Lutz Schwerin von Krosigk], undated (Box 5)
  See also: Item 45b.
- Item 46e. "Die Zerstörung der Familie,", 1947 (Box 5)
  Includes English translation ("Desintegration [sic] of Families").
- Item 46f. "The United States of Europe,", undated (Box 5)
- Item 47a. Problems with the denazification procedure, Eugen Kogon, 1947 June 26 (Box 5)
- Item 47b. "Operations of the 3rd Mtz Div[ision] (from October 1944 to 13 April 1945)," Werner Paul Abramovsky, former Major, undated (Box 5)
  Manuscript translated from Russian, then from German.
- Item 47c. "Combat Operations Against the US Army (from 2 January to 9 May 1945)," Otmar Richard Elwanger, former Hauptmann, undated (Box 5)
- Item 47d. "Operations Against American Army Troops (from 5 June to Approximately 30 June 1944)," E. Mauer, former Lieutenant Colonel, undated (Box 5)
  Manuscript translated from Russian, then from German (5 September 1946).
- Item 47e. "Defensive Battles Against the Americans and British [from 6 September to 1 November 1944]," Joseph Alois Rauch, former Generalmajor, undated (Box 5)
- Item 47f. "Operations Against American Troops in France," Schmidt, former Generalmajor, undated (Box 5)
  Manuscript translated from German and/or Russian.
- Item 48a. Correspondence re the Spanish Blue Division, 1951 (Box 5)
  Includes a letter from Dr. R. Schneider to Col. Philp, 2 March 1951; a letter in German, along with an English translation, from Merker to Col. Philp, 9 March 1951; and a letter from Merker to Col. Philp, 20 July 1951. The Spanish Blue Division fought with the Germans in a Russian campaign in 1943.
- Item 48b. "Bericht," Agnes von Heyden Gräfin von Cartlow, 1947 May (Box 5)
  Includes English translation ("Report"). Details her personal experience with the war, particularly after the arrival of Russian troops in 1945.
- Item 48c. English translation of a report on Austria's political parties, their background, and their development, Otto A. A. Baron von Bolschwing, 1949 September 1 (Box 5)
- Item 48d. "Gedanken zur derzeitigen Denazifizierungspolitik," Hans Jacobs, 1946 November 24 (Box 5)
  Includes cover letter of 26 November 1946, as well as an English translation of the cover letter and report ("Notes on the Present Denazification Policy").
- Item 49. Intelligence report on Dr. Josef Müller, State Minister of Justice and Deputy Minister President of Bavaria, 1950 May 23 (Box 5)
- Item 50a. "The Alpine Passes" [Adolph Heusinger], [1949] (Box 5)
  General Project No. J-214. Study (with annexes) written at the request of Col. Philp.
- Item 50b. "Comments on the Study 'The German Army High Command (OKH) Within the Framework of the High Command of the Armed Forces,'" Heinz Guderian, 1948 June (Box 5)
- Item 51. Headquarters, United States Forces in the European Theater, Military Intelligence Service Center, "Economics: A German View,", 1946 January 11 (Box 5-6)
  Includes introduction and description of methods ("The German View: Second Investigation"), as well as a short report, "Some Germans Talk," with observations and opinions from Graf Schwerin (General der Panzer Truppen), J. Riecke (Undersecretary for Agriculture under Hitler), Dr. Karl Hettlage (financial expert of the Speer Ministry), and Dr. Helmut Fischer (Reference III C-1 of the Sicherheits Dienst).
- Item 52. "Allgemeine Lagebetrachtung,", 1946 August (Box 6)
  Includes an English translation ("General Survey of the Situation") and three extensive annexes.
- Item 53. CLOSED
- Item 54a. "Description of Milita[r]y Operations Against American Army (Period from 6 June 1944 to 11 May 1946 [sic])," Dr. Georg Hermann Haselbach, former Oberstleutnant (Box 6)
  Manuscript translated from Russian, then from German (1 September 1946).
- Item 54b. "Military Operations Against American Troops in Africa," Hause, former Generalleutnant, undated (Box 6)
  Manuscript translated from Russian, then from German (19 September 1946).
- Item 54c. "Military Operations in Italy [from 22 January 1944 to May 1945]," Wilhelm Johann Hecht, former Major, undated (Box 6)
  Manuscript translated from Russian, then from German (2 September 1946).
- Item 54d. "Operations Against the American Army in Italy," Klatt, former Generalleutnant, undated (Box 6)
  Manuscript translated from Russian, then from German (10 September 1946).
- Item 54e. "Military Operations Against Anglo-American Troops on the Italian Front," Knappe, former Major, undated (Box 6)
- Item 55. Headquarters, United States Forces in the European Theater, Military Intelligence Service Center, "German Finance and Tax Policy: A Report on Operation Meeting Place,", 1946 January 12 (Box 6)
- Item 56. Headquarters, United States Air Force, Air P/W Interrogation Detachment, Military Intelligence Service, "A Crack German Panzer Division and What Allied Air Power Did to It Between D-Day and V-Day,", 1945 May 29 (Box 6)
- Item 57. Office of Military Government for Germany (U.S.), Office of the Director of Intelligence, Field Information Agency - Technical, "Report on the Connections with Speer's Plots Against Leading Nazis of Dietrich Stahl, Head of the Main Committee for Munitions in the Speer Ministry,", 1945 November 10 (Box 6)
  Includes cover letter dated 15 November 1945.
- Item 58. Headquarters, United States Forces in the European Theater, Military Intelligence Service Center, Intermediate Interrogation Report No. 59, "The Ostro Intelligence Source in England,", 1947 March 5 (Box 6)
  Source: Paul Fidrmuc, alias Ostro. Photocopy.
- Item 59. "Estimate of a Possible Soviet Plan for Strategic Concentration and Attack in Central Europe,", 1949 April (Box 6)
  Includes maps.
- Item 60. Miscellaneous material, 1943-1948, undated (Box 6, Box 10)
  Der Europäische Raum [map], 1943
  "Keep It Covered If You Want to Save It! Camouflage" [flyer], reproduced by 654th Engineers, U.S. Army, 1944
  "What You've Got, How Much You've Got, Where You've Got It: What the Enemy Wants to Know. Camouflage" [flyer], reproduced by 654th Engineers, U.S. Army, 1945
  Headquarters, United States Forces in the European Theater, Military Intelligence Service Center, "The German Church View," 1946 February 28
  "On the Nazi Gallows," translation of an excerpt from the Neuer Mainzer Anzeiger of 17 October 1946
  Handwritten letter, in German, 1946 October 18
  Two memoranda regarding a "Yugoslav patriot," Mr. Bozic, 1947 May 20
  Summary sent to Col. Philp regarding the Deutscher Orden, 1948 September 26
  Annex No. 1 to Periodic Report No. 111, "The Long Range German Rocket," undated
  Propaganda leaflets aimed at German soldiers, undated
  Poster, NSDAP Gau Köln-Aachen Öffentliche Versammlung, undated
  "Identity papers Issued by the German Army" [flyer], undated
  Photograph depicting Adolf Hitler, Hermann Göring, Benito Mussolini, and others during maneuvers of the Wehrmacht in 1937 [in box 10]
- Item 61. Military orders, maps, and photographs relating to the 6 June 1944 invasion of the Normandy coast, 1944-1945, 1948 (Boxes 6-8)
  Memoranda, reports, and charts regarding personnel, organization, orders, ammunition and supplies, intelligence, and communications, circa 1944
  "Operation Neptune: Force 'O' Intelligence Briefing Notes," circa 1944
  "List of Papers" [operations memoranda and maps], 1944 May
  "Movement Order, Command Alternate Command Groups," 1944 May 31
  Operations plans, memoranda, charts, and maps related to Operation Neptune, 1944 June
  "Personal Message from the C-in-C," 21 Army Group, signed by General B. L. Montgomery, 1944 June 10
  Periodic Unit Report No. 1, V Corps Artillery, 1944 June 12
  Periodic Unit Report No. 2, V Corps Artillery, 1944 June 13
  "Recommended Artillery Paragraph," V Corps Artillery, 1944 June 13
  "Conference at 2100 Hours," present: General Bradly, General Corlett, Major General L. T. Gerow, 1944 June 14
  "Restriction on Ammunition Expenditures," 1944 June 14
  "Excerpts from Bn orders," translation, 1944 July 8
  Field Order No. 21 [advance in France], 1944 August
  "Further Extracts from the Telephone Journal of Seventh German Army," 1944 August 6
  "Further Extracts from the Telephone Journal of Seventh German Army," 1944 August 7
  "Roster of Officers and Warrant Officers, by Sections, as of 15 August 1944," 1944 August 16
  Message from Headquarters, First U.S. Army, Office of the Artillery Officer," circa 1944 August 24
  Telegram from Corps Artillery, circa 1944 August 25
  "Movement of Balance of Forward Echelon," 1944 August 26
  "Extracts from Telephone Journal of Seventh Army," circa 1944 September 9
  "Ammunition Expenditures," 1945 January 12
  "Roster of Officers and Warrant Officers, by Sections and Units Attached to Headquarters, as of 15 January 1945," 1945 January 16
  "Roster of Officers and Warrant Officers, by Sections and Units Attached to Headquarters, as of 15 February 1945," 1945 February 16
  "Roster of Officers and Warrant Officers, by Sections and Units Attached to Headquarters, as of 15 March 1945," 1945 March 16
  "Ammunition Statistics," 1945 May 13
  Special Orders No. 27, "Individual Service Award of the Bronze Service Arrowhead," 1945 May 29
  Roster of officers, enlisted personnel, and civilians [includes addresses in Germany], 1948 December 10
  Rosters, undated
  Telegram from Dye to Artillery Commander, undated
  Maps (of France, specifically Normandy and its beaches, including an annotated waterproof map showing the invasion strategy) and landing diagrams, circa 1944
  Military aerial reconnaissance photos of the Normandy coast prior to the D-Day invasion, 1943-1944